# Mohammad Shahriari

Game Developer – C#, Unity, .Net

moh.shah96@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mohshah (portfolio) moh-shah.github.io

Experienced Unity Developer with extensive knowledge in mobile live-games and +5 years of coding experience. Specialized in software engineering and game development, proficient in designing game software architecture, core mechanics and enhancing player experiences on mobile platforms.

# **EXPERIENCES:**

**Unity Developer**, Medrick FZE, Sep 2020 – January 2024 (3 years and 4 months)

- As the technical lead for <u>Mighty Wars</u>, an online turn-based PvP game, I led a team of 3 client developers and 1 server developer. Besides leading the tech team, as a client developer, I was responsible for developing core game mechanics and designing the architecture of gameplay systems. Additionally, I implemented several other systems, including tracking analytics events, AB testing, interactive tutorials, and live ops events.
- Contributed as a member of the company's technical chapter, collaborating on the development of technical pipelines and visions.
- Participated in the architectural design and development of the company's in-house infrastructure for a <u>Live Ops System</u>.
- Maintained and extended the <u>Hokm</u> project, a multiplayer card game, through regular updates.
- Developed social features, including chat, groups, and friends, for <a href="Emma's Mansion">Emma's Mansion</a> project, a match-3 game with a decoration meta. Also worked on building its iOS version.
- Maintained and extended <u>BabaShah</u> and "Heshmat" projects, which share the same gameplay but have different meta, taking over from the main developer who left the studio.

# Back-End Developer, Part Games Studio, MAY 2019 – JULY 2020 (1 year and 2 months)

- Developed backend systems for profile management, purchase verification, and matchmaking in a real-time PvP game <u>Battle Arena</u>. Utilized .Net Core, MongoDB, and socket programming.
- Created a server application for profile management, leaderboard, chat, and purchase verification in the idle-clicker game "King Keyvan," using .Net Core and MongoDB.
- Developed a socket-based server application for a real-time strategy/tycoon game designed for a 2-day educational event called "Game-In" at Sharif University of Technology.

## Unity Developer, Part Games Studio, May 2018 – May 2019 (1 YEAR)

Developed a story-driven point and click adventure game called "Lost Days" for Android.

- Contributed to the client-side development of the real-time multiplayer strategy project called Game-In.
- Worked on the development of a project called "mini games," creating approximately 10 different mini-games as an Android application.

#### **Game Designer, Teetotum, November 2017 – May 2018 (7 Months)**

- Designed a puzzle game from concept to publication, including level design and complete Game Design Document (GDD) creation.
- Contributed to the design of the economy system for the game.
- Managed the publishing phase, including app store screenshot designs and descriptions.

# **EDUCATION:**

Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering, Azad University, Central Tehran Branch

## **SKILLS:**

- Software Engineering:
  - o Proficient in software architecture design.
  - Knowledgeable in design patterns and principles such as SOLID and code smells.
  - o Experienced in practicing Test-Driven Development (TDD) methodologies.
- C#:
  - o Expertise in C# programming language, including advanced features like multi-thread programming, LINQ, reflection, and asynchronous programming.
- Unity:
  - o Proficient in Unity engine, specializing in game development for mobile devices and WebGL.
  - Skilled in Android build tools and experienced with iOS app build pipelines.
  - Familiarity and up-to-date knowledge of new Unity technologies, including Addressables, Localization, Net Code, UI Toolkit, and DOTS.
- Back-End Development and Networking:
  - o In-depth understanding of network architectures such as client-server and P2P.
  - Experience with TCP, UDP, and WebSocket communications.
  - o Proficient in developing web APIs using .NET and .NET Core.
  - Knowledgeable in working with databases such as MongoDB, SQL Server, and in-memory databases like Redis.
  - o Familiarity with the Nakama Back-End Framework.
  - o Familiarity with Photon and Mirror.

- o Understanding of Docker and container concepts.
- Gameplay Programming:
  - Proficient in implementing core mechanics from scratch. From ideation and rapid prototyping to production-level implementation.
  - Skilled in implementing interactive tutorials for core-game mechanics.
- Experience working in Scrum-based environments and adhering to Scrum principles.
- Version Control Tools and Principles:
  - o Proficient in using Git, including Git commands, git flow, and branching rules.
  - o Knowledgeable in code review and merge policies.

# LANGUAGES:

• English (Proficient)

Persian (Native)